YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series V. Program Subjects
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. PROGRAM SUBJECTS
  - Subseries E. Religion
    - Publications and Resource Materials
      - YWCA religious program
        - Principles of Religious Practice in the Community Association Program by Winnifred Wygal, 1938 (Box 654, Folder 16)
        - The Religion of A Growing Person by Marie Russ, 1939 (Box 655, Folder 1)
        - Security in Crisis: Business Girls Seek Creative Religion by Alison H. Currie, 1942 (Box 655, Folder 2)
        - Testing a High School Girl's Belief, 1923 (Box 655, Folder 3)
        - The Touchstone: Christian Faith and the YWCA by Kathleen W. MacArthur, 1946 (Box 655, Folder 4)
        - "The YWCA: Our Faith," by Kathleen MacArthur, typescript, 1945 (Box 655, Folder 5)
        - YWCA Purpose: Lodestar of the Movement by Edith M. Lerrigo, 1974 (Box 655, Folder 6)
      - Biblical study and exegesis
        - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1908-19 (Box 655, Folder 7)
        - The Bible as a Community Book by Arthur E. Holt, 1920 (Box 655, Folder 8)
        - Brief Studies for Personal Workers by Elizabeth A. Labaree, 1917 (Box 655, Folder 9)
        - The Drama of Esther by the class in Religious Pedagogy at the National Training School, 1919 (Box 655, Folder 10)
        - Early Portraits of Jesus by Katharine L. Richards Rockwell, 1937 (Box 655, Folder 11)
        - Fundamentals for Daily Living by Robert Seneca Smith, 1921 (Box 655, Folder 12)
        - The Golden Word: Some Adventures in the Bible by Katharine L. Richards, 1919 (Box 655, Folder 13)
        - How to Study the Bible by F.C. Eiselen, 1912 (Box 655, Folder 14)
        - How to Use the Bible by L. Wendell Fifield, 1920 (Box 655, Folder 15)
        - Jesus among His Friends by Ethel Cutler, 1915 (Box 655, Folder 16)
        - Jesus' Teachings about Life: An Outline Study by Sara S. Kirk (Box 655, Folder 17)
        - Jesus the Man of Galilee by Elvira J. Slack, 1916 (Box 655, Folder 18)
        - Knowing Jesus as a Friend by Bertha Eckert, 1920 (Box 656, Folder 1)
        - Lessons in the Gospel of John by Charlotte H. Adams, 1912 (Box 656, Folder 2)
        - The Man who Gave Us Christmas by Winifred Kirkland, 1940 (Box 656, Folder 3)
        - The Manhood of the Master by Harry Emerson Fosdick, 1920 (Box 656, Folder 4)
        - The Message of the Earlier Prophets to Israel by Margaret G. Brooke, 1908-1912 [hand dated] (Box 656, Folder 5)
        - The Mind of the Messiah by Charlotte H. Adams, 1914 (Box 656, Folder 6)
        - Morning Times: Five Meditations on the Book of Ruth for Personal or Group Use, 1976 (Box 656, Folder 7)
        - My Friendship with Jesus Christ by Maud S. Davis, 1920 (Box 656, Folder 8)
        - On Openness by Grace Loucks Elliott and Jean Elliott Johnson, 1967 (Box 656, Folder 9)
        - One People among Many by Ethel Cutler, 1942 (Box 656, Folder 10)
        - One Prophet and Another by Ethel Cutler, 1941 (Box 656, Folder 11)
        - Out-of-Doors in the Bible by Ethel Cutler, 1913 (Box 657, Folder 1)
        - The Parables of Jesus by Elbert Russell, 1912 (Box 657, Folder 2)
        - Paul the Conqueror by Mary Redington Ely, 1919 (Box 657, Folder 3)
        - Resources for Bible Study and Prayer for Groups of Different Christian Backgrounds by Grace Loucks Elliott, 1961 (Box 657, Folder 4)
        - The Servant of the Lord by Adelaide Teague Case, 1940 (Box 657, Folder 5)
        - Short Meditations on Spiritual Resources by Charlotte H. Adams, 1933 (Box 657, Folder 6)
        - The Shorter Bible: The New Testament by Charles Foster Kent, 1918 (Box 657, Folder 7)
        - The Social Message of Jesus by Edward S. Parsons, 1912 (Box 657, Folder 8)
        - The Social Message of the Book of Revelation by Raymond Calkins, 1920 (Box 657, Folder 9)
        - Songs of Out of Doors: A Study Course by Adelaide P. Bostick, 1925 (Box 657, Folder 10)
        - The Story of Jesus as Mark Told It by Sara S. Kirk, 1916 (Box 657, Folder 11)
        - Studies in Knowing Jesus Christ by Helen Thoburn, 1919 (Box 657, Folder 12)
        - Studies in the Way of Jesus by Helen Thoburn, 1919 (Box 657, Folder 13)
        - The Supreme Gospel: A Study of the Epistle to the Hebrews by Hugh Thomson Kerr, 1918 (Box 658, Folder 1)
        - Take Your Choice by Charles Stafford Brown, 1935 (Box 658, Folder 2)
        - Ten Commandments in the Twentieth Century by Oolooah Burner, 1920 (Box 658, Folder 3)
        - They Told about Jesus by Ethel Cutler, 1943 (Box 658, Folder 4)
        - Towards a New Way of Life, 1920 (Box 658, Folder 5)
        - The Untried Door by Richard Roberts, 1921 (Box 658, Folder 6)
        - The Way of Christ by Alexander C. Purdy, 1918 (Box 658, Folder 7)
        - The Way of Jesus by Almira F. Holmes: 1923, three volumes, The Way of Jesus with His Friends, The Way of Jesus with His Father, and The Way of Jesus with the People Women of Ancient Israel by Charlotte H. Adams, 1912 (Box 658, Folder 8-9)
        - Women's Liberation in a Biblical Perspective by Letty Mandeville Russell, 1971 (Box 658, Folder 10)
      - Prayers and hymns
        - Miscellaneous, 1914-67, n.d. (Box 658, Folder 11)
        - A Book of Prayers by Helen Wright Mahon, 1952, 1960 (Box 659, Folder 1)
        - Fellowship Prayers by Sarah Truslow Dickinson, 1918 and 1921 editions; rev. ed., 1928 (Box 659, Folder 2)
        - A Little Book of Weeks, 1919 (Box 659, Folder 3)
        - Match Us to This Hour by Lilace Reid Barnes, 1964 (Box 659, Folder 4)
        - The Meaning of Prayer by Harry Emerson Fosdick, 1919 (Box 659, Folder 5)
        - Prayers for a Busy Day by Mary Chapin White, 1938 (Box 659, Folder 6)
        - Prayers of the Free Spirit edited by Stephen Hole Fritchman, 1945 (Box 659, Folder 7)
        - Prayers…Timely and Timeless, 1944, 1953 (Box 659, Folder 8)
        - Watch and Pray by the National Student Council, 1941 (Box 659, Folder 9)
    - Worship Services
      - Miscellaneous programs, 1912-86, n.d. (Box 659, Folder 10)
      - A Book of Services for Group Worship, 1929 (Box 659, Folder 11)
      - Certain Spiritual Practices by Anne Seesholtz, 1930 (Box 659, Folder 12)
      - The Chalice and the Cup by Mary S. Edgar, 1920 (Box 659, Folder 13)
      - Christmas Preparatory Services by Belle C. Morrill and Laura Huber, 1924 (Box 659, Folder 14)
      - Come Let Us Worship by Kathleen W. MacArthur, n.d. (Box 659, Folder 15)
      - Explorers: A Camp Project by Marion Dudley, 1926 (Box 659, Folder 16)
      - Four Services for Associations by Abbie Graham, 1927 (Box 660, Folder 1)
      - How to Make Group Devotions Vital by Oolooah Burner, 1932 (Box 660, Folder 2)
      - How to Plan Informal Worship by Winnifred Wygal, 1960 (Box 660, Folder 3)
      - How to Prepare Services of Worship: For Use in Clubs by Helen McCandless, 1940 (Box 660, Folder 4)
      - In Spirit and in Truth: A Convocation Service for the Young Women's Christian Association by Hazel MacKaye, 1920 (Box 660, Folder 5)
      - No Man unto Himself: Services of Worship on Interdependence by Rose Terlin, 1942 (Box 660, Folder 6)
      - One Father of All: A Vesper Service by Pearl Forsyth and Martha Race, 1921 (Box 660, Folder 7)
      - Planning Services of Worship by Ruth Perkins, 1931 (Box 660, Folder 8)
      - Reflections of the Spirit by Winnifred Wygal, 1948 (Box 660, Folder 9)
      - A Service for Grace Dodge Day, 1925 (Box 660, Folder 10)
      - A Service of Thanksgiving and Rededication, 1948 (Box 660, Folder 11)
      - Services for Special Needs by Lucy T. Bartlett, 1941 (Box 660, Folder 12)
      - Seven Psalms by Adelaide Teague Case, 1935 (Box 660, Folder 13)
      - Suggestions for Worship for Use at Board Meetings by Mrs. Frank C. Atherton, 1938 (Box 660, Folder 14)
      - These Things Shall Be, Brooks Spivy, 1939 (Box 660, Folder 15)
      - Three Services for Industrial Groups, 1927 (Box 660, Folder 16)
      - Three Vesper Services, 1924 (Box 660, Folder 17)
      - Twelve Services for Use by the Young Women's Christian Association, 1924 (Box 660, Folder 18)
      - Two World Fellowship Vesper Services, 1921 (Box 660, Folder 19)
      - We Plan Our Own Worship Services by Winnifred Wygal, 1940 (Box 660, Folder 20)
      - We Worship Together by Helen Wright Mahon, 1952 (Box 660, Folder 21)
      - Yet in One Voice We Give Thee Thanks, 1955 (Box 660, Folder 22)